<resources>

    <string-array name="AboutUsArray">
        <item>About</item>
        <item>Quality Instruction</item>
        <item>Capstone Projects</item>
        <item>Computer Laboratories</item>
        <item>Use of the Latest Software</item>
        <item>Tutoring/Advising</item>
        <item>Free Student Access to Software</item>
        <item>Preparation for Graduate School</item>
        <item>Networking with Industry</item>
        <item>Student Networking</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="AboutUs">
        Do I really need to worry about the department itself?

        Absolutely!  No matter where you go to school, your major is determined by the faculty that
        comprise that particular department.  These professors are the individuals whom you will
        spend a lot of time with in classes, laboratories and in completing homework assignments and
        projects.  They help to shape your future and take great interest in their students.

        You’ll find SVSU’s Department of Computer Science and Information Systems is staffed by
        qualified, competent professionals who are committed to teaching and research.  We are here
        to help you grow and succeed in your academic and professional career.  Our class sizes are
        small compared to other institutions and you’ll get to know and work with the CSIS faculty
        one-on-one.  This helps to foster a learning environment aimed at student success.
    </string>

    <string name="QualityInstruction">
        Faculty have the necessary education and experience to bring real world knowledge into their
        classrooms.  SVSU prides itself on being a teaching institution and the Department
        continually strives to provide the best instruction on campus.  Our programs and our
        curriculum are continually evaluated and change as the computing field and industry evolve.
        We put a lot of effort into trying to keep our programs as up-to-date as possible and bring
        in new technology wherever we can.
    </string>

    <string name="CapstoneProjects">
        How would you like to work on a real-world project while still an undergraduate?  That’s
        exactly what the capstone projects in each major do.  When you are a senior you’ll find out
        what it’s really like to be in industry because you’ll be building up a large scale system
        under the guidance of a CSIS faculty member.  Few other institutions afford their students
        this unique learning opportunity.
    </string>

    <string name="ComputerLaboratories">
        You’ll find that the university provides numerous computer labs throughout the campus that
        are automatically updated with the newest equipment every two to three years.  Additionally,
        the CSIS Department has specialized labs for computer networking, computer forensics and
        capstone classes/projects.  Furthermore most faculty use the online VSpace electronic
        learning environment to enrich your education.
    </string>

    <string name="UseOfTheLatestSoftware">
        The Department provides hands-on instruction using the latest and most popular software
        packages available, including both open source and commercial systems such as Visual Studio,
        PHP, C++, Linux, Windows, IIS, Apache, Microsoft Project, Visio, mySQL, Oracle, SQL Server,
        Expression Studio and DreamWeaver
    </string>

    <string name="TutoringAdvising">
        Need some extra help?  We have tutors available to help students out when they need it.
        The caring faculty of the Department also maintain regular office hours and are ready to
        assist whenever called upon.  We also work with students in planning their schedules through
        one-on-one advising as well as offering career information.
    </string>

    <string name="FreeStudentAccessToSoftware">
        The CSIS Department uses open source software where applicable and students may freely
        download the same software for their personal computers.  The Department also participates
        in the Microsoft Academic Alliance which means that students have free access to the same
        applications, development tools, operating systems and server software for their personal
        computers as that used in classes and labs.
    </string>

    <string name="PreparationforGraduateSchool">
        We have had many students interesting in going on to grad school.  Those students who did
        pursue higher education found that they were well prepared from their undergrad studies.
        Many faculty provide opportunities for students to participate in research projects and/or
        independent studies that allow students to further pursue their personal interests.
        Students receive shared credit for the research and often  present at conferences.
    </string>

    <string name="NetworkingWithIndustry">
        The Department maintains close ties to local industry.  This means that CSIS students have
        the ability to land internships, co-op positions and part-time employment in their field
        while still an undergraduate.  In addition to a paycheck, the experience this opportunity
        provides goes a long way toward landing that first job after graduation.  Many employers
        also contact the Department directly when they are looking to hire new recruits for full
        time positions.
    </string>

    <string name="StudentNetworking">
        Want more face-to-face time with your peers?  The Department has an active student chapter
        of the Association for Computing Machinery (ACM).  This group puts on numerous talks,
        training sessions and gaming nights each year as well as hosting the annual high school
        programming contest.  The ACM is a professional society and becoming active as a student
        looks great on your resume.  You may even consider sharpening your leadership skills by
        becoming a board member of the chapter.
    </string>
</resources>
