<resources>
    <string name="app_name">SVSU-CSIS (CS-403)</string>

        <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
        <string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>

        <!-- Usernames -->
        <string name="gpcorser">George Corser</string>
        <string name="kafzal">Komal Afzal</string>   <!-- kafzal -->
        <string name="adarenas">Alejandro Arenas</string>   <!-- adarenas -->
        <string name="bjcobb">Brian Cobb</string>   <!-- bjcobb -->
        <string name="pjessenm">Philip Essenmacher</string>   <!-- pjessenm -->
        <string name="gxhender">Gerald Henderson</string>   <!-- gxhender -->
        <string name="tskosask">Tyler Kosaski</string>   <!-- tskosask-->
        <string name="rtmegerl">Richard Megerle</string>   <!-- rtmegerl -->
        <string name="tpmetiva">Tyler Metiva</string>   <!-- tpmetiv1 -->
        <string name="zmmetiva">Zach Metiva</string>   <!-- zmmetiva -->
        <string name="alpero">Adam Pero</string>   <!-- alpero -->
        <string name="mdroof">Michael Roof</string>   <!-- mdroof -->
        <string name="jmwalter">Joshua Walters</string>   <!-- jmwalter -->
        <string name="ntwhitfi">Nathan Whitfield</string>   <!-- ntwhitfi -->
        <string name="amyork">Andrew York</string>   <!-- amyork -->


        <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
        <string name="gpcorser_bio">Great humanitarian</string>
    <string name="gpcorser_dept_desc">Department Description</string>
    <string name="gpcorser_dept_desc_text1">Inside the classroom</string>
    <string name="gpcorser_dept_desc_text2">Outside the classroom</string>
    <string name="gpcorser_dept_desc_text3">The Computer Science program and Computer Information Systems program share many of the same core classes to ensure that students are adequately prepared with the necessary background for their upper class studies.  This common core includes programming both in a Windows graphical environment as well as in a UNIX command-line environment.  Industry uses both operating systems and so the Department wants students to be well versed in each area.  Additionally, students will learn C++ and Microsoft Visual Basic as toolsets to develop applications.  The common core also includes introductory data structures, statistics with computer applications, web client development and web server development.  Both majors are heavily programming-oriented.  The curriculum has been designed this way on purpose so that students can learn about a concept and then use their programming knowledge as a vehicle to understand, experiment and implement that topic.  Both programs do a great job in preparing students for their future in industry or to pursue a graduate degree</string>
    <string name="gpcorser_difference_cs_cis">Difference Between CS and CIS</string>
    <string name="CIS_Title">CIS</string>
    <string name="CIS_Web">
        <![CDATA[
        <html>
            <body>
                <h3>Computer Information Systems</h3>
                <p>The Computer Information Systems program and Computer Science program share many of the same core classes to ensure that students are adequately prepared with the necessary background for their upper class studies.  This common core includes programming both in a Windows graphical environment as well as in a Unix command-line environment.  Industry uses both operating systems and so the Department wants students to be well versed in each area.  Additionally, students will learn C++ and Microsoft Visual Basic as toolsets to develop applications.  The common core also includes introductory data structures, statistics with computer applications, web client development and web server development.  Both majors are heavily programming-oriented.  The curriculum has been designed this way on purpose so that students can learn about a concept and then use their programming knowledge as a vehicle to understand, experiment and implement that topic.  Both programs do a great job in preparing students for their future in industry or to pursue a graduate degree

Computer Information Systems tends to be more application oriented than Computer Science and geared toward application development with some business emphasis.  Computer Information Systems majors will see the following in their degree program:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Topical Coverage Synopsis: Models, technologies, systems and E-business strategies that are crucial in today’s businesses</li>
                    <li>Cutting-edge technology skills and knowledge:
                    <ul>
                        <li>Application Areas: Data Communications, Database, e-Commerce, .NET development</li>
                        <li>Technical Topics: system integration &amp; management, systems design and analysis, enterprise database systems &amp; transaction processing and much more</li>
                    </ul>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </body>
        </html>
        ]]>
    </string>
<string name="MissionInfo">The mission of the Department of Computer Science and Information Systems at SVSU is to provide an outstanding education to its students in accordance with the guidelines of the SVSU mission, to advance scholarship in the key domains of the computing and information systems sciences, and to engage in activities that improve the welfare of society and enhance the reputation of SVSU.  The department will provide its students with balanced programs which emphasize:
   \n
    \n - the knowledge of the core principles of computer science
    \n - the skills necessary to use computers to solve real-world problems
    \n - experience in implementing solutions with modern computing tools
    \n - the communication skills necessary to work effectively in a team
    \n - foster a high level of faculty/student interaction and mentoring
        \n
      \n  At the end of their programs at SVSU, the department expects CSIS students to be able to:
        \n
    \n - Solve problems by using skills in math, computer science, and technology
    \n - Design, implement, document and maintain computer systems
    \n - Communicate effectively both orally and in writing
    \n - Understand professional, ethical, legal, security and social issues and responsibilities
    \n - Apply their knowledge and skills as they start their professional careers
    \n - Work well both independently and collaboratively with diverse groups
    \n - Generate new and creative ideas
        \n
 \n After the successful completion of their degree requirements at SVSU:
        \n
   \n 1) Graduates shall demonstrate a thorough grounding in the fundamental principles and practices of computing and information systems, and those principles that underpin them.
    \n 2) Graduates shall demonstrate an understanding of the contexts in which computing is applied.
    \n 3) Graduates shall find employment in the computing profession and/or continue advanced studies in computer science or information systems.

</string>

    <!-- gpcorser -->


    <!-- alpero - news -->
    <string name="alpero_news_title1">SVSU Foundation raises $28 million in record fundraising campaign</string>
    <string name="alpero_news_title2">SVSU earns \'Best Dorms\' in Michigan ranking, No. 26 nationally</string>
    <string name="alpero_news_title3">SVSU welcomes expert on climate change effect on small islands </string>
    <string name="alpero_news_date1">September 16, 2015</string>
    <string name="alpero_news_date2">August 19, 2015</string>
    <string name="alpero_news_date3">August 28, 2015</string>
    <string name="alpero_news_content1">More than 200 new scholarships created

By J.J. Boehm

The Saginaw Valley State University Foundation announced it exceeded its $25 million goal and raised more than $28 million during the “Talent. Opportunity. Promise” campaign, making it the largest fundraising effort in university history.

The campaign resulted in a $5 million gift from the Herbert H. and Grace A. Dow Foundation to create the Herbert H. and Grace A. Dow STEM Scholars Network. It provides funding to support SVSU student and faculty research, as well as outreach efforts to improve STEM (science, technology, engineering, math) learning among K-12 schools in the Great Lakes Bay Region. The gift is the largest single donation in SVSU history.

“We are deeply grateful to our generous donors, who are committed to providing more scholarships for students, supporting our faculty, and advancing the Great Lakes Bay Region, which has been so supportive of SVSU throughout our history,” said SVSU President Donald Bachand.

At a celebration event with donors Wednesday, Sept. 16, Bachand reiterated the importance of “every gift counts” to demonstrate the impact of all gifts.

The campaign raised more than $8 million for STEM-related initiatives, as SVSU also received a total of $2.7 million from The Dow Chemical Company Foundation to establish the Dow Science and Sustainability Education Center. The center works to enhance STEM education at SVSU and regional K-12 schools.

An estimated 11,000 K-12 students returned to Great Lakes Bay Region classrooms this year to be taught by teachers who participated in STEM professional development experiences offered at SVSU this summer. In addition, SVSU students and faculty are engaged in a number of STEM-based research projects supported through endowments established during this campaign

Donors made major gifts to provide additional opportunities for SVSU students in a variety of other areas, too, including:

    A $2 million commitment from Bob and Bobbi Vitito to fund the Vitito Global Leadership Institute for SVSU business students.
    A $1.5 million gift from the Harvey Randall Wickes Foundation to fund the Harvey Randall Wickes Endowed Chair in Nursing.
    A $1,183,500 gift from the Rollin M. Gerstacker Foundation to fund the Gerstacker Fellowship II and name the Gerstacker Regional Aquatics Center.
    A $1 million gift from the Herbert H. and Grace A. Dow Foundation to fund the Herbert H. and Grace A. Dow Foundation Student Research and Creativity Institute.

Scholarships

Creating additional scholarships was a key campaign priority, as state support for Michigan’s public universities has declined considerably over the years, placing a greater financial burden on students and their families. SVSU benefactors responded by creating more than 200 new scholarships for SVSU students to help defray the cost of their education.

“It was incredibly rewarding to see how donors responded to the call to increase funding for private scholarships,” said Jenee Velasquez, one of the campaign chairs, vice chair of SVSU’s Board of Control, and executive director of the Herbert H. and Grace A. Dow Foundation.  “While SVSU has an outstanding track record of maintaining affordability, we know that paying for college can be difficult for students and their families. Scholarship support sometimes can make all the difference in allowing a student to complete a degree and become a more productive member of society.”
Alumni

The campaign attracted unprecedented levels of alumni giving. More than 2,000 SVSU alumni contributed to the campaign, including two who share the honor of the largest single alumni gifts received. Jan Botz, a 1974 graduate, made a $1 million commitment to establish the Botz Liberal Arts Fellowship, which pairs students in the liberal arts with corporate partners for internships. Scott Carmona, a 1981 graduate and current chair of SVSU’s Board of Control, pledged $1 million to fund scholarships in business and engineering.

“As the youngest of Michigan’s public universities, many of our graduates are now reaching a stage in their lives and careers where they are in a position to give back to their alma mater, and we greatly appreciate their support,” said Andy Bethune, executive director of the SVSU Foundation. “Alumi giving was strong throughout the campaign, and we finished on a high note thanks to the Carmona Family Challenge.”

Included in the Carmona family gift was a challenge grant, where the family pledged to match all alumni gifts received between May 1 and August 15, and 484 alumni made gifts or pledges totaling more than $300,000 during that period.
Campaign Leadership and History

The “Talent. Opportunity. Promise” campaign began in 2011. It was chaired by:

    John Decker of Bay City, previously an attorney with Braun Kendrick before being hired as SVSU’s general counsel in 2013
    Brian Law of Bay City, chairman and CEO of Magline
    Herb Spence III of Saginaw, president of Spence Brothers
    Jenee Velasquez of Midland, executive director of the Herbert H. and Grace A. Dow Foundation

The $28 million raised during the “Talent. Opportunity. Promise.” campaign eclipses the $23 million generated during the “Promise for Tomorrow” campaign from 2005 to 2010. SVSU\'s “Campaign for Distinction” raised more than $13 million from 1997-99, and the “Creating the Future” campaign from 2000-02 exceeded $9.5 million.</string>
    <string name="alpero_news_content2">Saginaw Valley State University\'s campus housing facilities were ranked No. 1 in Michigan by a website grading “Best Dorms” in the United States.

SVSU was ranked No. 26 nationally.

The website, Niche, calculated the rankings using a weighted formula where 70 percent of a school’s score came from students\' satisfaction with their housing. The website surveyed 60,000 students from 903 colleges and universities. The rest of the formula was based upon housing costs, capacity and crime rates; each counted for 10 percent of the total score.

News of SVSU’s stellar review was no surprise to Ashley Murdock, an elementary education major from Oxford. She serves as president of the Residence Housing Association, a student organization for SVSU\'s residential population.

“We have such a positive energy here, and the residence halls are so homey,” the sophomore said. “We really take pride in them. This ranking doesn\'t surprise me.”

Before applying to SVSU, Mudrock had not visited the campus housing facilities.

“Once I saw the residence halls, I knew this was where I was supposed to be,” Murdock said. “It felt so welcoming and open. It felt like home.”

A new crop of Cardinals will have an opportunity to share that feeling when the fall semester begins. Residential students begin moving in Wednesday, August 26. Classes begin Monday, August 31.   More than 70 percent of the freshman class is expected to live on campus, continuing a seven-year trend.

“Once the semester starts, there\'s always something going on in the residence halls,” Murdock said. “There are a lot of really awesome programs.”

To view the "Best Dorms" list, go to https://colleges.niche.com/rankings/best-dorms/‌. </string>
    <string name="alpero_news_content3">Saginaw Valley State University will welcome a recognized authority on the effect of climate change on small island states. Lorna Veronica Inniss, acting director of the Coastal Zone Management Unit in Barbados, will speak Monday‌, Sept. 14 at 7:30 p.m. in SVSU’s Rhea Miller Recital Hall.

Climate change can be linked to a number of problems unique to small islands, such as rising sea levels that can result in decreased land area, warming sea surface temperatures, human health effects and natural environmental disasters. These are a few examples of the issues that impact the sociological, economic, and cultural futures of these small, independent nations.

Through her work with the Caribbean island nation of Barbados, Inniss has taken a leadership role in addressing this challenge. She serves as the island’s primary contact to the Intergovernmental Oceanographic Commission, and played a key role in developing the Barbados Program of Action for the Sustainable Development of Small Island Developing States. The program was adopted as a way to understand and address these special challenges; it was implemented within the United Nations Division for Sustainable Development.

Inniss also served as the elected chair of the U.N. Intergovernmental Coordination Group for the Caribbean Tsunamis and Coastal Hazards Warning System from 2008-2012. She is the joint coordinator of a group of experts established by the United Nations General Assembly to deliver the first ever Integrated Global Marine Assessment.  Later this year, Inniss will be taking a position as head of the Caribbean Environment Programme, United Nations Environment Programme. She completed a Ph.D. in oceanography and coastal sciences at Louisiana State University.

In addition to her public talk, Inniss also will meet with SVSU faculty, staff and students during her visit.</string>

     <string name="cs_opportunity"><![CDATA[\nWhere do our graduates go after graduation?
    \nSome students go on to complete graduate work and earn master’s degrees and Ph.D.s.  Our programs prepare students for grad school if that’s what they are interested in.  Many have pursued graduate degrees at institutions in the state such as Michigan State University, Oakland University, The University of Michigan and Central Michigan University.  Others have gone on to schools in other states and done very well.
    \nFor the majority of our students, they decide to enter the workforce after graduation.  Our name is recognized as producing skilled employees…a fact that we are very proud of.  In fact many local and regional employers return to SVSU year after year to hire our Computer Science and Information System student graduates.  Our students have even successfully started their own companies right after graduating from SVSU!
       \nSome will work for local companies such as      \nSaginaw Tooling Systems     \nThe Saginaw Intermediate School District     \nSVSU     \nDelta College     \nMahar Tools     \n...and many others  Regional employers attract others, like      \nAuto Owners Insurance     \nFrankenmuth Mutual Insurance     \nCovenant Healthcare     \nRehmann Group     \nMcLaren Health Care Corporation     \nAscension Health     \nYeo & Yeo     \n...among others  Others even make careers immediately at multinational corporations including
       \nDow Chemical     \nIBM     \nDow Corning     \nGeneral Motors     \nElectronic Data Systems     \nKPMG     \nDeloitte & Touche     \n...and yes, even Microsoft]]></string>

    <string name="sample_news">Saginaw Valley State University students and faculty will spend the next year helping a local pharmacist create a cleaner environment for the medicine formulated at his Saginaw Township-based compounding pharmacy laboratory.
        \n\nThe community partnership was formed when pharmacist Michael Collins asked James L. McEvoy, SVSU assistant professor of biology, to examine and identify the few bacteria found in the formulation lab at Collins\' Healthway Compounding Pharmacy. The results will help Collins create an even more sanitary environment for producing customized medicines.
        \n\n“Healthway is locally owned and has been supported by the community for 30 years,” Collins said. “Doing business locally is important to me. The science departments at SVSU have an outstanding reputation.”
        \n\nMcEvoy recommended conducting the research using a microbial identification system known as Biolog. Collins agreed to purchase the equipment; he has loaned the Biolog system to SVSU with the intent of donating the system to the university once the microbial identification research concludes next year.
        \n\n“It\'s a win-win situation for everyone involved,” said McEvoy, a former United States Department of Agriculture food safety lab researcher.  “Michael wants to find ways to improve his pharmacy. SVSU is working with a community partner and receiving state-of-the-art equipment. And one of my main goals is to introduce students to research.”
        \n\nCollins said he is excited about the partnership too.
        \n\n“I want to give back to our community and this is a great opportunity for Healthway to do that,” he said. “The SVSU biology department and the students will have an opportunity to use a state-of-the-art microbial identification system and Healthway will be able to keep their business needs local.”
        \n\nIn 2007, Healthway Compounding Pharmacy earned the distinction of being the first compounding pharmacy in Michigan to become accredited by the Pharmacy Compounding Accreditation Board (PCAB). PCAB-accredited compounding pharmacies must undergo inspections and meet strict standards for quality control and quality improvement. The pharmacy is committed to providing high quality, safe medications to patients, thus they conduct periodic environmental testing of the lab.
        \n\nSVSU\'s research will involve testing microbes captured from air samples collected during those environmental tests. In the university\'s laboratories, McEvoy and his students will isolate pure cultures of the microbes found in those samples and them run them through the Biolog metabolic fingerprinting system to identify.
        \n\nThe Biolog system includes equipment that analyzes the metabolic characteristics of the bacteria as well as computer software that cross-references those characteristics with a database of approximately 2,000 types of aerobic bacteria. The results indicate the most likely identities of the bacteria found.
        \n\nIdentifying the bacteria will help Collins understand how it entered the lab, and thus, how to prevent similar bacteria from entering in the future. McEvoy said a previously identified bacterium is typically found on human eyebrows, suggesting a pharmacy staff member scratching their eyebrow may have been the source of the microscopic intruder.
        \n\nMcEvoy expects to identify about 20 bacteria within the year.  Once the Healthway Compounding Pharmacy research is finished, McEvoy said he expects SVSU will use the Biolog system for teaching and faculty research while also offering research services to Healthway Compounding Pharmacy and other companies.
        \n\nIn 2015, SVSU received the Community Engagement classification from the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, a distinction achieved by only 7 percent of U.S. colleges and universities. For more on SVSU\'s community engagement, visit svsu.edu/communityengagement/.</string>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <string name="zmmetiva_title">Career Opportunities</string>
    <string name="zmmetiva_graduate">Where do our graduates go after graduation?</string>
    <string name="afterGradInfoTextView">Some students go on to complete graduate work and earn master’s degrees and Ph.D.s.  Our programs prepare students for grad school if that’s what they are interested in.  Many have pursued graduate degrees at institutions in the state such as Michigan State University, Oakland University, The University of Michigan and Central Michigan University. Others have gone on to schools in other states and done very well. For the majority of our students, they decide to enter the workforce after graduation.  Our name is recognized as producing skilled employees…a fact that we are very proud of.  In fact many local and regional employers return to SVSU year after year to hire our Computer Science and Information System student graduates.</string>
    <string name="afterGraduateInfo2TextView">Our students have even successfully started their own companies right after graduating from SVSU!</string>
    <string name="zmmetiva_titleText1">Opprotunities</string>
    <string name="zmmetiva_titleText2">Local Employers</string>
    <string name="zmmetiva_titleText3">Regional Employers</string>

=======

        <string name="tpmetiva_acm_desc">The Association For Computing Machinery (ACM) was founded in 1947. It is an international scientific and educational organization dedicated to advancing art, science, engineering and application of information technology. The ACM serves both professional and public interest by fostering the open interchange of information and promoting the highest professional and ethical standards.</string>
        <string name="tpmetiva_ieee_desc">The Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) is an international organization offering professional membership for engineers and scientists throughout the world. With a membership of over 360,000 in about 150 countries, IEEE is the world\'s largest professional technical society. The goals of IEEE focus on the promotion and advancement of knowledge and practice of electrical, electronics and computer engineering and computer science. To achieve these goals, 35 technical societies provide specialized membership within IEEE. In addition, over 800 worldwide Student Branches are sponsored by IEEE. \n\n\ The SVSU IEEE Student Branch , established in 1986, is open to EE and CS students, who are enrolled on at least a 50% full-time basis. Students enrolled in an allied branch of engineering, engineering technology or the related arts and sciences are also eligible for membership.\n\nFor more information and an application for membership contact any of the following:\n</string>
>>>>>>> bc7161049cbc417415655d5628daf4cc81dcd9e5
</resources>
