<resources>
    <string name="app_name">SVSU-CSIS (CS-403)</string>

        <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
        <string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>

        <!-- Usernames -->
        <string name="gpcorser">George Corser</string>
        <string name="kafzal">Komal Afzal</string>   <!-- kafzal -->
        <string name="adarenas">Alejandro Arenas</string>   <!-- adarenas -->
        <string name="bjcobb">Brian Cobb</string>   <!-- bjcobb -->
        <string name="pjessenm">Philip Essenmacher</string>   <!-- pjessenm -->
        <string name="gxhender">Gerald Henderson</string>   <!-- gxhender -->
        <string name="tskosask">Tyler Kosaski</string>   <!-- tskosask-->
        <string name="rtmegerl">Richard Megerle</string>   <!-- rtmegerl -->
        <string name="tpmetiv1">Tyler Metiva</string>   <!-- tpmetiv1 -->
        <string name="zmmetiva">Zach Metiva</string>   <!-- zmmetiva -->
        <string name="alpero">Adam Pero</string>   <!-- alpero -->
        <string name="mdroof">Michael Roof</string>   <!-- mdroof -->
        <string name="jmwalter">Joshua Walters</string>   <!-- jmwalter -->
        <string name="ntwhitfi">Nathan Whitfield</string>   <!-- ntwhitfi -->
        <string name="amyork">Andrew York</string>   <!-- amyork -->


        <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
        <string name="gpcorser_bio">Great humanitarian</string>
    <string name="gpcorser_dept_desc">Department Description</string>
    <string name="gpcorser_dept_desc_text1">Inside the classroom</string>
    <string name="gpcorser_dept_desc_text2">Outside the classroom</string>
    <string name="gpcorser_dept_desc_text3">The Computer Science program and Computer Information Systems program share many of the same core classes to ensure that students are adequately prepared with the necessary background for their upper class studies.  This common core includes programming both in a Windows graphical environment as well as in a UNIX command-line environment.  Industry uses both operating systems and so the Department wants students to be well versed in each area.  Additionally, students will learn C++ and Microsoft Visual Basic as toolsets to develop applications.  The common core also includes introductory data structures, statistics with computer applications, web client development and web server development.  Both majors are heavily programming-oriented.  The curriculum has been designed this way on purpose so that students can learn about a concept and then use their programming knowledge as a vehicle to understand, experiment and implement that topic.  Both programs do a great job in preparing students for their future in industry or to pursue a graduate degree</string>
    <string name="gpcorser_difference_cs_cis">Difference Between CS and CIS</string>
    <!-- gpcorser -->
</resources>
